Tzu-Sheng Kuo

(650) 391-5684tskuo@stanford.edutskuo.github.io

I design and help others create interactive systems that improve user experience with mobile devices and responsive environments to support people's well-being. My research interest in HCI is at the intersection of digital fabrication, sensing and interaction techniques, and application to human health, behavior change, and assistive technologies.

Education

2019 - Jun 2021 Stanford University.

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering, GPA: 4.00/4.00

2014 - 2019 National Taiwan University (NTU).

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering, GPA: 4.25/4.30, Summa Cum Laude (Top 1%)

Research Experience

Human-Computer Interaction

2019 - Present Stanford HCl Group, Stanford, CA.

Advisors: Prof. James Landay, Prof. Elizabeth Murnane

- o Redesigned digital interfaces to support user well-being by adopting nature elements into user interfaces
- o Resulted in one publication in submission to CHI 2021
- 2017 2019 Interactive Graphics Lab, NTU, Taiwan.

Advisors: Prof. Bing-Yu Robin Chen, Prof. Xing-Dong Yang

- o Designed two pneumatic interfaces that emulate physical objects to provide haptic feedback in VR
- o Designed a software tool with an autocomplete feature to assist makers in building breadboard circuits
- o Resulted in three publications at UIST 2018, UIST 2019, and CHI 2019

Computer Vision & Machine Learning

2017 - 2019 Vision and Learning Lab, NTU, Taiwan.

Advisor: Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang

- o Modified DeepLabv3+ and proposed a loss function for semantic segmentation on satellite imagery
- o Resulted in one publication at DeepGlobe Workshop in CVPR 2018

Signal Processing

2016 - 2019 Multimedia Processing and Communications Lab, NTU, Taiwan.

Advisor: Prof. Homer H. Chen

- o Approximated the temporal variation of gaze fixation to estimate the depth based on eye vergence
- o Resulted in one publication at ICIP 2018

Peer-Reviewed Publications

CHI 2021 **Tzu-Sheng Kuo**. Kelsey Wang, Sarah L. Billington, James A. Landay, and Elizabeth L. Murnane. 2021. Biophilic Technology: Exploring the Application of Biophilic Principles to the Design of Digital Interfaces. In Submission to *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI '21). ACM, New York, NY, USA. [under review]

UIST 2019 Shan-Yuan Teng, Cheng-Lung Lin, Chi-huan Chiang, Tzu-Sheng Kuo, Liwei Chan, Da-Yuan Huang, and Bing-Yu Chen.

2019. TilePoP: Tile-type Pop-up Prop for Virtual Reality. In *Proceedings of the 32nd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology* (UIST '19). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 639–649.

Best Paper Honorable Mention [PDF]

CHI 2019 Jo-Yu Lo, Da-Yuan Huang, Tzu-Sheng Kuo, Chen-Kuo Sun, Jun Gong, Teddy Seyed, Xing-Dong Yang, and Bing-Yu Chen.

2019. AutoFritz: Autocomplete for Prototyping Virtual Breadboard Circuits. In *Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI '19). ACM, New York, NY, USA, Paper 403, 1–13.

Best Paper Honorable Mention [PDF]

UIST 2018 Shan-Yuan Teng, **Tzu-Sheng Kuo**, Chi Wang, Chi-huan Chiang, Da-Yuan Huang, Liwei Chan, and Bing-Yu Chen. 2018. PuPoP: Pop-up Prop on Palm for Virtual Reality. In *Proceedings of the 31st Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology* (UIST '18). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 5–17. [PDF]

CVPRW 2018 **Tzu-Sheng Kuo***, Keng-Sen Tseng*, Jia-Wei Yan*, Yen-Cheng Liu, and Yu-Chiang Frank Wang. 2018. Deep Aggregation Net for Land Cover Classification. In *IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Workshops* (CVPRW '18). Salt Lake City, UT, pp. 252–256. *The authors contributed equally. [PDF]

ICIP 2018 **Tzu-Sheng Kuo**, Kuang-Tsu Shih, Sheng-Lung Chung, and Homer H. Chen. 2018. Depth from Gaze. In 25th IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP '18). Athens, pp. 2910–2914. [PDF]

Posters and Demos

UIST 2020 **Tzu-Sheng Kuo** and Eric Rawn. 2020. Let It Rip! Using Velcro for Acoustic Labeling. In *The Adjunct Publication of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology* (UIST '20). [PDF]

(a project mentored by Prof. Michael Bernstein at Stanford)

HCOMP 2020 Tzu-Sheng Kuo, McArdle Hankin, Miranda Li, Andrew Ying, and Cathy Wang. 2020. Assessing Political Bias using

• Crowdsourced Pairwise Comparisons. In *Proceeding of the 8th AAAI Conference on Human Computation and Crowdsourcing* (HCOMP '20). [to appear]

Best Poster Award

(a project mentored by Prof. Maneesh Agrawala at Stanford)

Teaching Experience

- 2018 Teaching Assistant, Computer Vision: from Recognition to Geometry Instructor: Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang
- 2018 Teaching Assistant, Deep Learning for Computer Vision Instructor: Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang
- 2017 Teaching Assistant, Machine Learning Instructor: Prof. Hung-Yi Lee
- 2017 Teaching Assistant, Signals and Systems Instructor: Prof. Lin-Shan Lee
- 2016 Teaching Assistant, Electronics I Instructor: Prof. Liang-Hung Lu

Honors and Awards

- 2020 Stanford Graduate Student Research Assistantship
- 2018 Phi Tau Phi Scholastic Honor Society Honorary Membership Graduated top 1% in NTU EECS Department
- 2014 2018 Dean's List (5 times) Top 5% GPA in each semester
 - 2018 Chien Shih-Liang Memorial Scholarship Given to two students in NTU EECS Department each year
 - 2017 Taiwan Ministry of Science and Technology Research Grant
 - 2017 Irving T. Ho Memorial Scholarship Given to one senior student in NTU EE Department each year

University Service

2020 - Present HCI Qualifying Exam DEI Proposal Group

I collaborated with graduate students and faculty members to develop a proposal to add readings that center on diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) to the HCI qualifying exam at Stanford.

2020 - Present Graduate Residence Community Associate

I work with the Stanford Graduate Life Office and other community associates on promoting wellness and a sense of community in graduate residences with 1200+ students by coordinating social events and responding to emergencies.

Leadership Experience

2016 - 2018 Founder, Makerspace of NTUEE &

My team and I founded a makerspace to assist students in doing their side projects. During COVID-19, out students developed a system that was deployed across the campus to automatically detect and track people's forehead temperature.

2017 Chair, MakeNTU Makeathon §

My team and I launched the first nationwide makeathon in Taiwan with 200 participants and 70K USD in sponsorship. I led 60 students and cooperated with the Taipei City Government and 22 companies such as Google and Microsoft.

2016 - 2017 Director, Academic Department of NTUEE Student Association &

I led a team of 30 students to organize various university events, including research competitions, award ceremonies, NTU university fairs, and NTUEE+ alumni mixers for over 800 students in the EE department.

Work Experience

- 2019 Mandatory Military Service, Taiwan.
- 2017 Software Engineering Intern, Cadence Design Systems, Inc., San Jose, CA.
 - o My code for Gate-Level and RTL circuit design automation was checked-in for production and I received a return offer.

Technical Skills

Technical Skills Python, C++/C#, Matlab, Tensorflow, PyTorch, React, Javascript, CSS, HTML, Unity, OpenCV, Verilog, etc.

Languages English (fluent), Mandarin (native), Taiwanese (native)